Abraham: With the large amount of
malware out there it will inevitably
penetrate and infect a system
especially a vulnerable system.
This infection maybe caused by downloading
a music file, a video file, or any
other software from suspicious sites.
Also clicking on a link from a
suspicious email sent from an unknown
email address or even one pretending
to be from a trusted contact.
The most common signs that a system
has been compromised are when a
computer slows down, browsers redirect
to other sites, infection warnings,
offers of software to buy to fix
it and pop-up ads, also, problems
shutting down and starting up a system.
Any of these may suggest
that a system is infected.
So how can you stop this happening?
Make sure that your system is protected by
legitimate 'anti-malware' purchased from
a reputable company even if it is a mobile
system and that it is kept up to date,
both the operating system and any software
installed on it such as your web browser.
Keep all devices secure and don't download
anything from any dodgy sites or click on
any unknown links on unreliable emails.
Only purchase from official suppliers.
But if you do find that you have
Malicious software infecting
your system, can it be removed?
It is possible to remove malware, by
running a scan using the security software
installed on the device or system and
taking steps to fix the web browser.
Antimalware works in two different ways.
The first is a more outdated
approach which works on creating
a hash of all files on the system.
This hash is then checked against a
list of known malicious hashed malware.
This is referred to as
signature-based detection.
The problem with this method is that
it relies on the fact that the malware
has been previously identified and
at the pace at which malware is being
developed this is becoming harder to do.
In response to this a lot of antimalware
solutions now work on a heuristic
detection method, which looks more at
the behaviours of files or processes
in a system to identify what could
be potentially malicious behaviour.